[
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of MASS is&",
    "answer": "grams (g)"
  },
  {
    "question": "When light hits a TRANSPARENT object, it&",
    "answer": "goes through"
  },
  {
    "question": "A bar magnet can be DEMAGNETISED by&",
    "answer": "[EITHER of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "A force of 3N at a distance of 8cm will have what turning moment?",
    "answer": "3×8=24 Ncm3 \\times 8 = 24\\text { Ncm}3×8=24 Ncm"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is ELECTRICITY generated?",
    "answer": "[ALL of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a planet?",
    "answer": "The Sun"
  },
  {
    "question": "We measure ELECTRICAL CURRENT with&",
    "answer": "an ammeter"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of TIME is&",
    "answer": "hours (h)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A sound wave with a SMALLER AMPLITUDE would be&",
    "answer": "quieter"
  },
  {
    "question": "A MAGNETIC field exists around&",
    "answer": "a wire carrying a current"
  },
  {
    "question": "Snowshoes can be worn to ---(1)--- the PRESSURE on the ground by ---(2)--- the area over which their weight is applied.",
    "answer": "1: decrease; 2: increasing"
  },
  {
    "question": "The SUN is the ultimate source of the energy for...",
    "answer": "[ALL of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these objects in the SOLAR SYSTEM is the LARGEST?",
    "answer": "The Earth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is a component which gives off LIGHT?",
    "answer": "An LED"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term ACCELERATION is used in physics to mean a CHANGE IN VELOCITY. That means that ACCELERATION can be used to describe&",
    "answer": "[ALL of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "SOUND can be DETECTED by...",
    "answer": "a microphone which produces an electrical signal from a vibrating diaphragm"
  },
  {
    "question": "An ELECTROMAGNET can be made stronger by which of the following?",
    "answer": "INCREASING the current"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a HYDRAULIC system&",
    "answer": "the PRESSURE of the LIQUID is UNIFORM"
  },
  {
    "question": "CHEMICAL energy is turned to KINETIC energy by&",
    "answer": "a car's engine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these objects in the SOLAR SYSTEM is the SMALLEST?",
    "answer": "A comet"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ---(1)--- breaks the circuit if a fault in an appliance causes too much ---(2)--- to flow.",
    "answer": "1: fuse; 2: current"
  },
  {
    "question": "Too much weight on a spring will cause&",
    "answer": "disproportional extension"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: When an object vibrates, LIGHT is produced.",
    "answer": "[FALSE]: SOUND is produced when an object vibrates"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the SECOND step in a RELAY switch?",
    "answer": "The magnetic field attracts an iron ARMATURE"
  },
  {
    "question": "The VOLUME of an irregularly-shaped solid can be found by...",
    "answer": "submerging the object and measuring the displacement of water"
  },
  {
    "question": "As a PENDULUM swings back and forth, it transfers energy from ---(1)--- energy into ---(2)--- energy as it falls, and vice versa as it comes back up again.",
    "answer": "1: gravitational potential; 2: kinetic"
  },
  {
    "question": "Our SOLAR SYSTEM is part of the MILKY WAY...",
    "answer": "galaxy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these converts ELECTRICAL energy to THERMAL energy?",
    "answer": "[BOTH of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "DOUBLING the weight hanging on a spring, assuming the ELASTIC LIMIT is NOT reached, will&",
    "answer": "DOUBLE the EXTENSION"
  },
  {
    "question": "PLANE mirrors can be used to construct...",
    "answer": "a periscope"
  },
  {
    "question": "INCREASING the LENGTH of a lever has what effect on the MOMENT of the force?",
    "answer": "It is INCREASED"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is a RENEWABLE energy source?",
    "answer": "Waves"
  },
  {
    "question": "Night and day happen because&",
    "answer": "the Earth spins on its axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "An LED will emit light if connected to a circuit&",
    "answer": "depending on the direction of current"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of DISTANCE is&",
    "answer": "light years (ly)"
  },
  {
    "question": "When drawing a RAY DIAGRAM, you should draw ARROWS on the light rays&",
    "answer": "pointing AWAY from the light source"
  },
  {
    "question": "Levers use the principle of ---(1)--- to reduce the FORCE needed for tasks. An example of a lever is ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: MOMENTS; 2: scissors"
  },
  {
    "question": "WIND power is a RENEWABLE energy source. An ADVANTAGE of WIND power is that ---(1)--- and a DISADVANTAGE is that ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: it does not require burning of fossil fuels; 2: its output can be unpredictable"
  },
  {
    "question": "A LUNAR ECLIPSE is caused by&",
    "answer": "the EARTH passing between the SUN & the MOON"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: For a current to flow in a simple circuit, the switches must be CLOSED.",
    "answer": "[TRUE]: The circuit must be COMPLETE"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of DISTANCE is&",
    "answer": "metres (m)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sound travels at a speed of over 300 m/s. Sound CANNOT travel through&",
    "answer": "a vacuum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which force applied at 5cm will produce a turning moment of 20 Ncm?",
    "answer": "4 N"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does electricity get generated in a POWER STATION?",
    "answer": "[ALL of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the MOON?",
    "answer": "Spherical"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of ELECTRICAL RESISTANCE is&",
    "answer": "ohms (©)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The DISTANCE travelled by an object can be calculated by&",
    "answer": "multiplying speed and time"
  },
  {
    "question": "Lightning is seen ---(1)--- thunder is heard because LIGHT travels ---(2)--- than SOUND.",
    "answer": "1: before; 2: faster"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used to measure PRESSURE is&",
    "answer": "N/cm²"
  },
  {
    "question": "A RENEWABLE energy source is...",
    "answer": "a source which can be REPLENISHED in a lifetime"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these objects in the SOLAR SYSTEM is the LARGEST?",
    "answer": "Jupiter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is a component which gives off LIGHT?",
    "answer": "A bulb"
  },
  {
    "question": "Less FRICTION occurs if surfaces are&",
    "answer": "smooth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Decreasing the AMPLITUDE of a loudspeaker makes the sound it produces&",
    "answer": "quieter"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does a HYDRAULIC LIFT work?",
    "answer": "Uniform pressure in a liquid MULTIPLIES the force by applying it to a LARGER area"
  },
  {
    "question": "A SKIER who is waiting to start skiing down a slope has&",
    "answer": "Gravitational Potential Energy (GPE)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these sequences showing the order of bodies in the SOLAR SYSTEM is in the WRONG order?",
    "answer": "Sun’Venus’Mercury’Earth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these converts ELECTRICAL energy to LIGHT energy and THERMAL energy?",
    "answer": "A bulb"
  },
  {
    "question": "We measure FORCES with&",
    "answer": "a spring balance"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: Blowing a saxophone HARDER will make the sound QUIETER.",
    "answer": "[FALSE]: It makes it LOUDER"
  },
  {
    "question": "To calculate the MASS of an object, you can MULTIPLY ---(1)--- by ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: its DENSITY; 2: its VOLUME"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ENERGY of a system will tend to be ---(1)--- over time as it is ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: lost; 2: converted to heat"
  },
  {
    "question": "EARTH is the ---(1)--- PLANET away from the ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: third; 2: SUN"
  },
  {
    "question": "When light hits an ---(1)--- its RESISTANCE ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: LDR; 2: decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Quadrupling the load on a spring but halving its length will produce&",
    "answer": "twice the original extension"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a light ray passes through the boundary of two transparent materials of different densities (e.g. from air to water), the direction of the ray will be altered. This effect is known as&",
    "answer": "refraction"
  },
  {
    "question": "The VOLUME of a liquid can be measured using...",
    "answer": "a measuring cylinder"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a stationary object is moved from a low shelf and placed onto a higher shelf, its KINETIC energy afterwards is ---(1)--- and its GRAVITATIONAL POTENTIAL energy is ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: UNCHANGED; 2: INCREASED"
  },
  {
    "question": "The MOON moves around the EARTH because of the&",
    "answer": "gravitational attraction between the two masses"
  },
  {
    "question": "Components all connected on the SAME branch of a circuit are&",
    "answer": "in series"
  },
  {
    "question": "We can measure DISTANCE (length or width) with&",
    "answer": "[ANY of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unlike ---(1)---, light is able to travel through a ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: sound; 2: vacuum"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: The SUN is the ultimate source of the\nenergy for FOSSIL FUELS.",
    "answer": "[TRUE]: The SUN provided energy for prehistoric plants to photosynthesise; that energy is now stored in fossil fuels"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long does it take the MOON to orbit the EARTH?",
    "answer": "27 days  (roughly 1 month)"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: For a current to flow in a simple circuit, a CELL must NOT be connected.",
    "answer": "[FALSE]: A cell MUST be connected"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of ACCELERATION is&",
    "answer": "metres per second squared (m/s2^{2}2)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would best be described as TRANSLUCENT?",
    "answer": "FROSTED GLASS: It allows light to pass through, but with significant INTERFERENCE"
  },
  {
    "question": "The THIRD stage in the formation of FOSSIL FUELS is&",
    "answer": "CHEMICAL energy is stored in the remains of living organisms in the Earth's surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "The movement of the Sun across the sky can safely be observed by&",
    "answer": "watching a sundial"
  },
  {
    "question": "We measure ELECTRICAL POTENTIAL with&",
    "answer": "a voltmeter"
  },
  {
    "question": "More FRICTION occurs if surfaces are&",
    "answer": "rough"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: Sound travels at a SLOWER speed than light.",
    "answer": "[TRUE]: Sounds travels at a speed UNDER 300,000,000 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "If you put these four stages of production of ELECTRICITY in a POWER STATION in order, which one would go THIRD?",
    "answer": "The TURBINE turns the GENERATOR"
  },
  {
    "question": "The MILKY WAY is the name of our&",
    "answer": "GALAXY, which contains BILLIONS of stars"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of ELECTRICAL POTENTIAL is&",
    "answer": "volts (V)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A car will encounter more FRICTION on&",
    "answer": "a DRY tarmac road"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: Hitting a drum more SOFTLY will make the sound LOUDER.",
    "answer": "[FALSE]: It makes it QUIETER"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which form of energy does a falling cannonball have?",
    "answer": "Kinetic"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these objects in the SOLAR SYSTEM is the CLOSEST to the EARTH?",
    "answer": "The Moon"
  },
  {
    "question": "A battery or cell transforms ---(1)--- energy into ---(2)--- energy.",
    "answer": "1: chemical; 2: electrical"
  },
  {
    "question": "The TIME taken by an object to travel a DISTANCE can be calculated by&",
    "answer": "dividing distance by speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "SOUND waves are produced when objects vibrate. An example of this is...",
    "answer": "a loud speaker"
  },
  {
    "question": "A SKIER who is waiting to start skiing down a slope has&",
    "answer": "Gravitational Potential Energy (GPE)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these sequences showing the order of bodies in the SOLAR SYSTEM is in the WRONG order?",
    "answer": "Sun’Venus’Mercury’Earth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these converts ELECTRICAL energy to LIGHT energy and THERMAL energy?",
    "answer": "A bulb"
  },
  {
    "question": "We measure FORCES with&",
    "answer": "a spring balance"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: Blowing a saxophone HARDER will make the sound QUIETER.",
    "answer": "[FALSE]: It makes it LOUDER"
  },
  {
    "question": "As a PENDULUM swings back and forth, it transfers energy from ---(1)--- energy into ---(2)--- energy as it falls, and vice versa as it comes back up again.",
    "answer": "1: gravitational potential; 2: kinetic"
  },
  {
    "question": "Our SOLAR SYSTEM is part of the MILKY WAY...",
    "answer": "galaxy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these converts ELECTRICAL energy to THERMAL energy?",
    "answer": "[BOTH of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "DOUBLING the weight hanging on a spring, assuming the ELASTIC LIMIT is NOT reached, will&",
    "answer": "DOUBLE the EXTENSION"
  },
  {
    "question": "PLANE mirrors can be used to construct...",
    "answer": "a periscope"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a cannonball is dropped, its GRAVITATIONAL POTENTIAL energy is transferred to ---(1)--- energy. The total amount of energy is ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: KINETIC; 2: UNCHANGED"
  },
  {
    "question": "MAN-MADE satellites are used for&",
    "answer": "[ALL of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "The CURRENT in a SERIES circuit...",
    "answer": "is the same at all points"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of DISTANCE is&",
    "answer": "kilometres (km)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ---(1)--- camera consists of a box with a translucent screen at one end and a tiny hole made in the other end. The image on the translucent screen is upside down and ---(2)--- than the object",
    "answer": "1: pinhole; 2: smaller"
  },
  {
    "question": "In any system, TOTAL ENERGY is always ---(1)---, but in doing work some energy will be dissipated into ---(2)--- useful forms.",
    "answer": "1: CONSERVED; 2: LESS"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of GRAVITATIONAL FIELD STRENGTH is&",
    "answer": "N/kg"
  },
  {
    "question": "Components which are connected to DIFFERENT branches of a circuit are&",
    "answer": "in parallel"
  },
  {
    "question": "We can measure WEIGHT with&",
    "answer": "a Newton meter"
  },
  {
    "question": "A RAINBOW is a natural example of the...",
    "answer": "dispersion of white light"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the SUN?",
    "answer": "Spherical"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a simple circuit with ONE CELL and ONE bulb, the bulb is producing \"normal brightness\". Adding ANOTHER BULB means that the bulbs would each now produce&",
    "answer": "LESS brightness (i.e. they would be DIMMER)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of MASS is&",
    "answer": "grams (g)"
  },
  {
    "question": "When light hits a TRANSPARENT object, it&",
    "answer": "goes through"
  },
  {
    "question": "A SOLAR ECLIPSE is caused by&",
    "answer": "the MOON passing between the SUN & the EARTH"
  },
  {
    "question": "An LDR INCREASES resistance as&",
    "answer": "light decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of MASS is&",
    "answer": "kilograms (kg)"
  },
  {
    "question": "When light hits a POLISHED SURFACE, it&",
    "answer": "reflects"
  },
  {
    "question": "The movement of the Sun across the sky can safely be observed by&",
    "answer": "watching a sundial"
  },
  {
    "question": "We measure ELECTRICAL POTENTIAL with&",
    "answer": "a voltmeter"
  },
  {
    "question": "More FRICTION occurs if surfaces are&",
    "answer": "rough"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: Sound travels at a SLOWER speed than light.",
    "answer": "[TRUE]: Sounds travels at a speed UNDER 300,000,000 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is a DWARF planet?",
    "answer": "Pluto"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of ELECTRICAL CURRENT is&",
    "answer": "amps (A)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The SPEED of an object can be calculated by&",
    "answer": "dividing distance by time"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sound travels through vibrations in&",
    "answer": "[ALL of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "The PLANETS move around the Sun because of&",
    "answer": "a combination of momentum and gravity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is drawn as a rectangle around the line of the wire?",
    "answer": "A fuse"
  },
  {
    "question": "Less FRICTION occurs if surfaces are&",
    "answer": "greased"
  },
  {
    "question": "The AMPLITUDE of a sound relates to its&",
    "answer": "loudness"
  },
  {
    "question": "MAN-MADE satellites are used for&",
    "answer": "[ALL of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these converts ELECTRICAL energy to KINETIC energy?",
    "answer": "A motor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a FORCE?",
    "answer": "Heat"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a tunnel, ---(1)--- occur when sound is ---(2)--- the walls.",
    "answer": "1: echoes; 2: reflected off"
  },
  {
    "question": "The nearest STAR to the Earth is&",
    "answer": "the Sun"
  },
  {
    "question": "MOTORS convert ELECTRICAL energy to...",
    "answer": "KINETIC and THERMAL energy"
  },
  {
    "question": "The same weight on TWO identical springs in SERIES compared to ONE spring produces&",
    "answer": "twice the original extension"
  },
  {
    "question": "The SIZE or MAGNITUDE of a vibration is called&",
    "answer": "amplitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Our SOLAR SYSTEM is part of the MILKY WAY...",
    "answer": "galaxy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these converts ELECTRICAL energy to THERMAL energy?",
    "answer": "[BOTH of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "DOUBLING the weight hanging on a spring, assuming the ELASTIC LIMIT is NOT reached, will&",
    "answer": "DOUBLE the EXTENSION"
  },
  {
    "question": "PLANE mirrors can be used to construct...",
    "answer": "a periscope"
  },
  {
    "question": "To calculate the WEIGHT of an object, you must MULTIPLY ---(1)--- by ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: its mass; 2: the gravitational field strength"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: For a current to flow in a simple circuit, the circuit must be INCOMPLETE.",
    "answer": "[FALSE]: The circuit must be COMPLETE"
  },
  {
    "question": "A unit used for the measurement of VELOCITY is&",
    "answer": "metres per second (m/s)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Light is produced from ---(1)--- and travels in ---(2)--- lines",
    "answer": "1: LUMINOUS sources; 2: straight"
  },
  {
    "question": "In places like the UK, the number of hours of DAYLIGHT each day ---(1)--- throughout the year. This is because of the ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: changes; 2: Earth's tilt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The VOLTAGE of a cell is measured by connecting the meter&",
    "answer": "in parallel"
  },
  {
    "question": "We would most likely measure the LENGTH of a tennis court with&",
    "answer": "a trundle-wheel"
  },
  {
    "question": "This process where light is ABSORBED and RE-EMITTED in all directions is called...",
    "answer": "SCATTERING"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is approximately the gravitational field strength at the EARTH's surface... [Check the units]",
    "answer": "10N/kg"
  },
  {
    "question": "The CURRENT in a circuit is measured by connecting the ammeter&",
    "answer": "in series"
  },
  {
    "question": "We can measure DISTANCE with&",
    "answer": "a tape measure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The splitting of the colours in white light (for example, when it passes through a prism) is called&",
    "answer": "dispersion"
  },
  {
    "question": "Removing one of the CELLS from a circuit would make the bulbs&",
    "answer": "dimmer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Weight is the FORCE that acts on a mass due to GRAVITY. It is NOT the same as mass. In science, the correct unit used for the measurement of WEIGHT is&",
    "answer": "newtons (N)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would best be described as OPAQUE?",
    "answer": "A WOODEN DOOR: It does NOT ALLOW any light to pass through at all"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a simple circuit with ONE CELL and ONE bulb, the bulb is producing \"normal brightness\". Adding ANOTHER CELL and ANOTHER BULB means that the bulbs would each now produce&",
    "answer": "normal brightness (as before)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A unit used for the measurement of VELOCITY is&",
    "answer": "kilometres per hour (km/h)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would best be described as COMPLETELY TRANSPARENT?",
    "answer": "A WINDOW: It allows light to pass through with NO INTERFERENCE"
  },
  {
    "question": "An LDR INCREASES resistance as&",
    "answer": "light decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of MASS is&",
    "answer": "kilograms (kg)"
  },
  {
    "question": "When light hits a POLISHED SURFACE, it&",
    "answer": "reflects"
  },
  {
    "question": "We measure ELECTRICAL CURRENT with&",
    "answer": "an ammeter"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of TIME is&",
    "answer": "hours (h)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A sound wave with a SMALLER AMPLITUDE would be&",
    "answer": "quieter"
  },
  {
    "question": "The POTENTIAL DIFFERENCE across an electrical component is measured by&",
    "answer": "a voltmeter"
  },
  {
    "question": "A car on a LOW-FRICTION surface might&",
    "answer": "skid"
  },
  {
    "question": "INCREASING the SIZE of the vibrations of a speaker (i.e. increasing its AMPLITUDE) makes the sound it produces&",
    "answer": "louder"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of ELECTRICAL POTENTIAL is&",
    "answer": "volts (V)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A car will encounter more FRICTION on&",
    "answer": "a DRY tarmac road"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: Hitting a drum more SOFTLY will make the sound LOUDER.",
    "answer": "[FALSE]: It makes it QUIETER"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is drawn as a rectangle around the line of the wire?",
    "answer": "A fuse"
  },
  {
    "question": "Less FRICTION occurs if surfaces are&",
    "answer": "greased"
  },
  {
    "question": "The AMPLITUDE of a sound relates to its&",
    "answer": "loudness"
  },
  {
    "question": "LDRs convert ELECTRICAL energy to...",
    "answer": "THERMAL energy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a FORCE?",
    "answer": "Mass"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete the following statement: sound travels at ---(1)--- speed which is ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: \"JET\"; 2: over 300 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "Electrical INSULATORS have extremely ---(1)--- resistance, this means that a very ---(2)--- current will flow through them.",
    "answer": "1: high; 2: small"
  },
  {
    "question": "A weight hung from a spring produces&",
    "answer": "an extension"
  },
  {
    "question": "SOUND waves are produced from...",
    "answer": "vibrating objects"
  },
  {
    "question": "Electrical CONDUCTORS have ---(1)--- resistance, this means that a ---(2)--- current will flow through them.",
    "answer": "1: low; 2: high"
  },
  {
    "question": "An object of 1kg mass on earth will have approximately how much WEIGHT?",
    "answer": "10N"
  },
  {
    "question": "Materials that SCATTER light are...",
    "answer": "translucent"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these converts ELECTRICAL energy to THERMAL energy?",
    "answer": "[BOTH of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "DOUBLING the weight hanging on a spring, assuming the ELASTIC LIMIT is NOT reached, will&",
    "answer": "DOUBLE the EXTENSION"
  },
  {
    "question": "PLANE mirrors can be used to construct...",
    "answer": "a periscope"
  },
  {
    "question": "LEDs convert ELECTRICAL energy to...",
    "answer": "[BOTH of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of DISTANCE is&",
    "answer": "metres (m)"
  },
  {
    "question": "When LIGHT cannot pass through an object, it produces a...",
    "answer": "shadow"
  },
  {
    "question": "The CURRENT in different PARALLEL branches of a complete circuit is&",
    "answer": "LESS than the current from the cell"
  },
  {
    "question": "We can measure WEIGHT with&",
    "answer": "[EITHER of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "A RAY DIAGRAM might be used to show the path of light as it hits a mirror and then reflects away. The angles of INCIDENCE and REFLECTION on that ray diagram could be measured with...",
    "answer": "a protractor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete the following statement: A ---(1)--- circuit can cause ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: short; 2: wires to melt"
  },
  {
    "question": "We would most likely measure THICKNESS of a hair with&",
    "answer": "a micrometer"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a VACUUM, light will travel...",
    "answer": "in straight lines"
  },
  {
    "question": "The CURRENT in a circuit is measured by connecting the ammeter&",
    "answer": "in series"
  },
  {
    "question": "We can measure DISTANCE with&",
    "answer": "a tape measure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The splitting of the colours in white light (for example, when it passes through a prism) is called&",
    "answer": "dispersion"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the function of a FUSE?",
    "answer": "To protect the circuit from high current"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these will INCREASE a car's stopping distance?",
    "answer": "A wet road"
  },
  {
    "question": "WHITE light is...",
    "answer": "a mixture of all colours"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is drawn as two lines, one short, one long?",
    "answer": "A cell"
  },
  {
    "question": "To calculate the DISTANCE moved by an object, you can MULTIPLY ---(1)--- by ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: its SPEED; 2: TIME taken"
  },
  {
    "question": "When light reaches the boundary between materials at an angle&",
    "answer": "its direction will be altered"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is drawn as a circled rectangle with two small inward-pointing arrows nearby?",
    "answer": "An L.D.R."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these will DECREASE a car's stopping distance?",
    "answer": "Slower driving speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these terms describes an object which CREATES light?",
    "answer": "Luminous"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is drawn as a circle containing the letter M?",
    "answer": "A motor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these encounters FRICTION?",
    "answer": "A JET'S WING moving through the AIR"
  },
  {
    "question": "When light is reflected at a plane mirror, the angle of emergence is&",
    "answer": "EQUAL to the angle of incidence"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of FORCE is&",
    "answer": "newtons (N)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes how LIGHT travels?",
    "answer": "In straight lines"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of DISTANCE is&",
    "answer": "light years (ly)"
  },
  {
    "question": "When drawing a RAY DIAGRAM, you should draw ARROWS on the light rays&",
    "answer": "pointing AWAY from the light source"
  },
  {
    "question": "A unit used for the measurement of VELOCITY is&",
    "answer": "kilometres per hour (km/h)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would best be described as COMPLETELY TRANSPARENT?",
    "answer": "A WINDOW: It allows light to pass through with NO INTERFERENCE"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of ACCELERATION is&",
    "answer": "metres per second squared (m/s2^{2}2)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would best be described as TRANSLUCENT?",
    "answer": "FROSTED GLASS: It allows light to pass through, but with significant INTERFERENCE"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of DISTANCE is&",
    "answer": "metres (m)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sound travels at a speed of over 300 m/s. Sound CANNOT travel through&",
    "answer": "a vacuum"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of TIME is&",
    "answer": "hours (h)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A sound wave with a SMALLER AMPLITUDE would be&",
    "answer": "quieter"
  },
  {
    "question": "A car will encounter more FRICTION on&",
    "answer": "a DRY tarmac road"
  },
  {
    "question": "Making a trombone's pipe LONGER&",
    "answer": "makes it LOWER PITCHED"
  },
  {
    "question": "The DISTANCE travelled by an object can be calculated by&",
    "answer": "multiplying speed and time"
  },
  {
    "question": "Lightning is seen ---(1)--- thunder is heard because LIGHT travels ---(2)--- than SOUND.",
    "answer": "1: before; 2: faster"
  },
  {
    "question": "A car will encounter more FRICTION on&",
    "answer": "a DRY tarmac road"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: Hitting a drum more SOFTLY will make the sound LOUDER.",
    "answer": "[FALSE]: It makes it QUIETER"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is slowed by&",
    "answer": "friction with the AIR"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these can travel through a vacuum?",
    "answer": "Light"
  },
  {
    "question": "Less FRICTION occurs if surfaces are&",
    "answer": "smooth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Decreasing the AMPLITUDE of a loudspeaker makes the sound it produces&",
    "answer": "quieter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a FORCE?",
    "answer": "Mass"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete the following statement: sound travels at ---(1)--- speed which is ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: \"JET\"; 2: over 300 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "Too much weight on a spring will cause&",
    "answer": "disproportional extension"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: When an object vibrates, LIGHT is produced.",
    "answer": "[FALSE]: SOUND is produced when an object vibrates"
  },
  {
    "question": "We measure FORCES with&",
    "answer": "a spring balance"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: Blowing a saxophone HARDER will make the sound QUIETER.",
    "answer": "[FALSE]: It makes it LOUDER"
  },
  {
    "question": "An object of 1kg mass on earth will have approximately how much WEIGHT?",
    "answer": "10N"
  },
  {
    "question": "Materials that SCATTER light are...",
    "answer": "translucent"
  },
  {
    "question": "The same weight on TWO identical springs in PARALLEL compared to ONE spring produces&",
    "answer": "half the original extension"
  },
  {
    "question": "A SHADOW is produced when...",
    "answer": "the path of light is BLOCKED by an object"
  },
  {
    "question": "Quadrupling the load on a spring but halving its length will produce&",
    "answer": "twice the original extension"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a light ray passes through the boundary of two transparent materials of different densities (e.g. from air to water), the direction of the ray will be altered. This effect is known as&",
    "answer": "refraction"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of DISTANCE is&",
    "answer": "metres (m)"
  },
  {
    "question": "When LIGHT cannot pass through an object, it produces a...",
    "answer": "shadow"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used for the measurement of DISTANCE is&",
    "answer": "kilometres (km)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ---(1)--- camera consists of a box with a translucent screen at one end and a tiny hole made in the other end. The image on the translucent screen is upside down and ---(2)--- than the object",
    "answer": "1: pinhole; 2: smaller"
  },
  {
    "question": "We can measure DISTANCE (length or width) with&",
    "answer": "[ANY of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unlike ---(1)---, light is able to travel through a ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: sound; 2: vacuum"
  },
  {
    "question": "We would most likely measure THICKNESS of a hair with&",
    "answer": "a micrometer"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a VACUUM, light will travel...",
    "answer": "in straight lines"
  },
  {
    "question": "We can measure the VOLUME of a liquid in a&",
    "answer": "measuring cylinder"
  },
  {
    "question": "A NON-LUMINOUS object can only be seen when light is ---(1)--- it and is then ---(2)--- our eyes",
    "answer": "1: reflected off; 2: absorbed by"
  },
  {
    "question": "We would most likely measure TIME in an experiment by&",
    "answer": "stopwatch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Materials that are ---(1)--- absorb light and re-emit it in all directions, this process is called ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: translucent; 2: SCATTERING"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these will INCREASE a car's stopping distance?",
    "answer": "A wet road"
  },
  {
    "question": "WHITE light is...",
    "answer": "a mixture of all colours"
  },
  {
    "question": "To calculate the TIME taken on a journey, you can DIVIDE ---(1)--- by ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: the DISTANCE travelled; 2: the SPEED of travel"
  },
  {
    "question": "WHITE LIGHT may be dispersed by&",
    "answer": "[ALL of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these encounters FRICTION?",
    "answer": "[ALL of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "WHITE LIGHT is made of seven colours. Choose the answer with the colours in order of DECREASING wavelength.",
    "answer": "Red - Orange - Yellow - Green - Blue - Indigo - Violet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these will DECREASE a car's stopping distance?",
    "answer": "Slower driving speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these terms describes an object which CREATES light?",
    "answer": "Luminous"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two cars travel in opposite directions and each have SPEED of 25m/s, the CLOSING speed is... [check the units]",
    "answer": "50m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do we see objects which do not emit light?",
    "answer": "Light is reflected off them to the eye"
  },
  {
    "question": "In force diagrams, the ---(1)--- of arrows represents the ---(2)--- of the force.",
    "answer": "1: DIRECTION; 2: DIRECTION"
  },
  {
    "question": "LIGHT travels&",
    "answer": "very, very, very fast (hundreds of MILLIONS of metres per second)"
  },
  {
    "question": "EQUILIBRIUM is when the NET force on an object...",
    "answer": "equals zero"
  },
  {
    "question": "Making something's vibrations MORE FREQUENT (i.e. more vibrations per second) makes the sound it produces&",
    "answer": "higher pitched"
  },
  {
    "question": "Weight is a&",
    "answer": "force"
  },
  {
    "question": "LOUD sounds can...",
    "answer": "cause temporary or permanent damage to hearing"
  },
  {
    "question": "Moving objects are slowed by&",
    "answer": "friction"
  },
  {
    "question": "A sound wave with a HIGHER FREQUENCY would be&",
    "answer": "higher-pitched"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the forces acting on an object are UNBALANCED, what happens to the object?",
    "answer": "Its speed and/or direction change"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FREQUENCY of a sound relates to its&",
    "answer": "pitch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Objects are pulled towards the Earth by&",
    "answer": "gravity"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do SOUND WAVES that reach the ear get heard?",
    "answer": "Sounds reaching the EARDRUM vibrate bones in the middle ear"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would best be described as COMPLETELY TRANSPARENT?",
    "answer": "Clear WATER: It allows light to pass through with NO INTERFERENCE"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would best be described as OPAQUE?",
    "answer": "MILK: It does NOT ALLOW light to pass through"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes how LIGHT travels?",
    "answer": "In straight lines"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would best be described as OPAQUE?",
    "answer": "A WOODEN DOOR: It does NOT ALLOW any light to pass through at all"
  },
  {
    "question": "When drawing a RAY DIAGRAM, you should draw ARROWS on the light rays&",
    "answer": "pointing AWAY from the light source"
  },
  {
    "question": "When light hits a TRANSPARENT object, it&",
    "answer": "goes through"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would best be described as COMPLETELY TRANSPARENT?",
    "answer": "A WINDOW: It allows light to pass through with NO INTERFERENCE"
  },
  {
    "question": "A LUMINOUS object&",
    "answer": "EMITS light"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would best be described as TRANSLUCENT?",
    "answer": "FROSTED GLASS: It allows light to pass through, but with significant INTERFERENCE"
  },
  {
    "question": "When light hits a POLISHED SURFACE, it&",
    "answer": "reflects"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sound travels at a speed of over 300 m/s. Sound CANNOT travel through&",
    "answer": "a vacuum"
  },
  {
    "question": "SOUND can be DETECTED by...",
    "answer": "[BOTH of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "A sound wave with a SMALLER AMPLITUDE would be&",
    "answer": "quieter"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: Sound travels at a SLOWER speed than light.",
    "answer": "[TRUE]: Sounds travels at a speed UNDER 300,000,000 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "Making a trombone's pipe LONGER&",
    "answer": "makes it LOWER PITCHED"
  },
  {
    "question": "INCREASING the SIZE of the vibrations of a speaker (i.e. increasing its AMPLITUDE) makes the sound it produces&",
    "answer": "louder"
  },
  {
    "question": "Lightning is seen ---(1)--- thunder is heard because LIGHT travels ---(2)--- than SOUND.",
    "answer": "1: before; 2: faster"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sound travels through vibrations in&",
    "answer": "[ALL of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: Hitting a drum more SOFTLY will make the sound LOUDER.",
    "answer": "[FALSE]: It makes it QUIETER"
  },
  {
    "question": "SOUND can be DETECTED by...",
    "answer": "a microphone which produces an electrical signal from a vibrating diaphragm"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these can travel through a vacuum?",
    "answer": "Light"
  },
  {
    "question": "The AMPLITUDE of a sound relates to its&",
    "answer": "loudness"
  },
  {
    "question": "Decreasing the AMPLITUDE of a loudspeaker makes the sound it produces&",
    "answer": "quieter"
  },
  {
    "question": "SOUND waves are produced when objects vibrate. An example of this is...",
    "answer": "a loud speaker"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete the following statement: sound travels at ---(1)--- speed which is ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: \"JET\"; 2: over 300 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a tunnel, ---(1)--- occur when sound is ---(2)--- the walls.",
    "answer": "1: echoes; 2: reflected off"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: When an object vibrates, LIGHT is produced.",
    "answer": "[FALSE]: SOUND is produced when an object vibrates"
  },
  {
    "question": "SOUND waves are produced from...",
    "answer": "vibrating objects"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: Blowing a saxophone HARDER will make the sound QUIETER.",
    "answer": "[FALSE]: It makes it LOUDER"
  },
  {
    "question": "The SIZE or MAGNITUDE of a vibration is called&",
    "answer": "amplitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Materials that SCATTER light are...",
    "answer": "translucent"
  },
  {
    "question": "REFRACTION is the ---(1)--- of light, when the light meets the ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: bending; 2: boundary between two different materials"
  },
  {
    "question": "A SHADOW is produced when...",
    "answer": "the path of light is BLOCKED by an object"
  },
  {
    "question": "PLANE mirrors can be used to construct...",
    "answer": "a periscope"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a light ray passes through the boundary of two transparent materials of different densities (e.g. from air to water), the direction of the ray will be altered. This effect is known as&",
    "answer": "refraction"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name for the BENDING of light at the boundary between materials?",
    "answer": "REFRACTION"
  },
  {
    "question": "When LIGHT cannot pass through an object, it produces a...",
    "answer": "shadow"
  },
  {
    "question": "Light is produced from ---(1)--- and travels in ---(2)--- lines",
    "answer": "1: LUMINOUS sources; 2: straight"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ---(1)--- camera consists of a box with a translucent screen at one end and a tiny hole made in the other end. The image on the translucent screen is upside down and ---(2)--- than the object",
    "answer": "1: pinhole; 2: smaller"
  },
  {
    "question": "A RAY DIAGRAM might be used to show the path of light as it hits a mirror and then reflects away. The angles of INCIDENCE and REFLECTION on that ray diagram could be measured with...",
    "answer": "a protractor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unlike ---(1)---, light is able to travel through a ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: sound; 2: vacuum"
  },
  {
    "question": "This process where light is ABSORBED and RE-EMITTED in all directions is called...",
    "answer": "SCATTERING"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a VACUUM, light will travel...",
    "answer": "in straight lines"
  },
  {
    "question": "A RAINBOW is a natural example of the...",
    "answer": "dispersion of white light"
  },
  {
    "question": "A NON-LUMINOUS object can only be seen when light is ---(1)--- it and is then ---(2)--- our eyes",
    "answer": "1: reflected off; 2: absorbed by"
  },
  {
    "question": "The splitting of the colours in white light (for example, when it passes through a prism) is called&",
    "answer": "dispersion"
  },
  {
    "question": "Materials that are ---(1)--- absorb light and re-emit it in all directions, this process is called ---(2)---.",
    "answer": "1: translucent; 2: SCATTERING"
  },
  {
    "question": "WAVES obey the LAW of REFLECTION, which states that&",
    "answer": "the angle of INCIDENCE = the angle of REFLECTION"
  },
  {
    "question": "WHITE light is...",
    "answer": "a mixture of all colours"
  },
  {
    "question": "When light hits a BLACK object, it&",
    "answer": "is absorbed"
  },
  {
    "question": "WHITE LIGHT may be dispersed by&",
    "answer": "[ALL of these]"
  },
  {
    "question": "When light reaches the boundary between materials at an angle&",
    "answer": "its direction will be altered"
  },
  {
    "question": "WHITE LIGHT is made of seven colours. Choose the answer with the colours in order of DECREASING wavelength.",
    "answer": "Red - Orange - Yellow - Green - Blue - Indigo - Violet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these can travel through a vacuum?",
    "answer": "Light"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these terms describes an object which CREATES light?",
    "answer": "Luminous"
  },
  {
    "question": "The separated colours of white light are called&",
    "answer": "a spectrum"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do we see objects which do not emit light?",
    "answer": "Light is reflected off them to the eye"
  },
  {
    "question": "When light is reflected at a plane mirror, the angle of emergence is&",
    "answer": "EQUAL to the angle of incidence"
  },
  {
    "question": "LIGHT travels&",
    "answer": "very, very, very fast (hundreds of MILLIONS of metres per second)"
  },
  {
    "question": "LIGHT travels&",
    "answer": "FASTER than sound"
  },
  {
    "question": "Making something's vibrations MORE FREQUENT (i.e. more vibrations per second) makes the sound it produces&",
    "answer": "higher pitched"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sound waves with FREQUENCIES higher than 20000Hz are called ---(1)---. These waves have FREQUENCIES ---(2)--- than the human hearing range.",
    "answer": "1: ultrasound; 2: higher"
  },
  {
    "question": "LOUD sounds can...",
    "answer": "cause temporary or permanent damage to hearing"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FREQUENCY of waves is measured in&",
    "answer": "hertz (HZ)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A sound wave with a HIGHER FREQUENCY would be&",
    "answer": "higher-pitched"
  },
  {
    "question": "Making a violin's string SHORTER&",
    "answer": "makes it HIGHER PITCHED"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FREQUENCY of a sound relates to its&",
    "answer": "pitch"
  },
  {
    "question": "If an object vibrates LESS FREQUENT (i.e. fewer times per second), the sound it produces is&",
    "answer": "lower pitched"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do SOUND WAVES that reach the ear get heard?",
    "answer": "Sounds reaching the EARDRUM vibrate bones in the middle ear"
  },
  {
    "question": "[TRUE or FALSE?]: Hearing can be damaged by exposure to loud noise.",
    "answer": "[TRUE]: The sound waves can damage the INNER EAR"
  },
  {
    "question": "A sound wave with a LONGER WAVELENGTH would be&",
    "answer": "lower-pitched"
  }
]
